# Ian Joshua Anderson

ij@ianjoshua.com | 831.601.9817

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **AUDIBLE** | PRODUCT MANAGER - CONTENT SYSTEMS June 2019 - Present | Newark, NJ

- Led product strategy and owned roadmaps for Audible's Content Systems, including internal and external products supported by over 40 engineers across 4 development teams
- Envisioned and oversaw execution of Audible's first fully automated content delivery pipeline to successfully meet Amazon D-Team goal
- Managed integral product for independent creators during COVID-19 that saw >400% YoY increase in new user registration
- Coordinated with Product and HR leadership to develop Audible's first Product Management Intern program, which launched successfully in summer 2019

#### **INFOBASE** | PRODUCT MANAGER

February 2015 - May 2018 | New York, NY

- Oversaw agile development of multiple products including an educational video streaming platform with tailored market solutions
- Developed opportunity, received investment, and managed development for Universal Admin Portal
- Charged to develop roadmap following acquisition of Learn360; evaluated needs, developed integration strategy, and attained approval at executive levels; successfully migrated 1M+ users at 10K+ institutions
- Launched MARC record utility, reducing customer wait time for content metadata records from 45 days to less than 24 hour, removed dependency on 3P vendor

### IJD | INDEPENDENT BUSINESS CONSULTANT

June 2010 - August 2016 | Carmel, CA & New York, NY

- Partnered with small business and NGO clients to understand organizational goals and implement digital transformation projects
- Led engagements throughout life cycle, including negotiation, solutions strategy, implementation, and relationship management
- Select Engagements:
  - Reduced scheduling department overhead by 65% for service business by redesigning procedures and calendar system
  - Developed online strategy for health education nonprofit, including technical implementation and staff training

#### **EDUCATION**

## **CORNELL TECH** | JOHNSON CORNELL TECH MBA May 2019 | New York, NY

- Merit Scholar; Dean's List; Emerging Markets Institute Fellow; Data Analytics TA; 1st Place, iTreck Hackathon, Tel Aviv, Israel
- Asine.me Led five-person multidisciplinary team, with support from Mastercard, using predictive analytics to improve sales efficiency

#### UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SANTA CRUZ | BA

Sociology; Global Information and Social Enterprise Studies

Sept. 2007 - June 2011 | Santa Cruz, CA

#### **PROFILE**

Proven product manager with experience in B2B and internal tools. A strong focus on data informed decision making while managing products at all stages of the development life cycle, and comfortable balancing priorities to see oversee multiple projects simultaneously.

#### SKILLS

#### CORE

Product Vision • Strategy
Data Informed Decision Making
Roadmaps • Voice of Customer
Cross-functional Communication
Product Leadership • Mentorship

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

AWS • System Design • SQL WordPress • HTML • CSS • APIs Agile • XML • Ruby on Rails Python • Serverless Architecture

#### ADDITIONAL

Cornell Tech Product Studio Advisor Everett Program Alumni Guest Lecturer on Product Management (multiple universities in NY area)

#### **INTERESTS**

Continuous learning methodologies Experiencing new cultures Personal productivity Reading (see ianjoshua.com/bookshelf for my recommended reading list)

#### LINKS

linkedin.com/in/ianjanderson/ianjoshua.com